Now I want to describe a notation which we call classical planning which is
现在我想介绍所谓的经典规划表示法
a representation language for dealing with states and actions and plans.
这种表示语言用于解决状态 动作和规划
And it's also an approach for dealing with the problem of
也可以通过将世界拆分为变量
complexity by factoring the world into variables.
解决复杂性问题
So under classical planning the state space consists of all the possible assignments to
在经典规划情况下 状态空间包含布尔变量
k-boolean variables and so that
所有可能存在的赋值
means they'll be two to the case states in that state space.
因此表示在这个状态空间中 会出现两种案例状态
And if we think about
如果我们考虑
the two location vacuum world we would have three boolean variables.
真空世界的两个地点 我们会得到三个布尔变量
We could have dirt in location A,
地点 A 有垃圾 (Dirt A)
dirt in location B and vacuum in location A.
地点 B 有垃圾 (Dirt B) 地点 A 有真空吸尘器 (Vac a)
And the vacuum has to be in either A or B.
真空吸尘器在地点 A 或 B
So these three variables will do and they'll be eight possible states in that world,
这三个变量可以做到 这个世界的 8 种可能的状态
but they can be succinctly represented through the three variables.
不过它们是通过三个变量准确表现出来的
And then World State consists of
然后通过三个变量
a complete assignment of true or false through each of the three variables.
世界状态包括真或假的完整赋值
And then a belief state.
然后是信度状态
Well, just as in problem
与问题解决相同
solving the belief state depends on what type of environment you want to deal with.
信度状态取决于你想要解决的环境类型
Now in the core classical planning the belief state had to
在核心经典规划中 信度状态必须
be a complete assignment and that was useful for dealing with deterministic,
是完整的赋值 那样才会在解决确定的
fully observable domains, but we can easily extend
充分观测的域内有效 但是我们可以很容易延伸
classical planning and we can deal with belief states that are partial assignments.
经典规划 可以解决部分赋值的信度状态
That is some of the variables have values and others don't.
即一些变量具有值 而另一些没有
So we could have the beliefs state consisting of vacuum in A is true and the others are
我们可以得到信度状态 其中包含真空吸尘器在 A 为真 其他未知
unknown and that small formula represents four possible world states.
这个小方程式表示了 4 个可能的世界状态
And we can even have a belief state which is
我们甚至可以得到信度状态
an arbitrary formula in boolean logic and that can represent anything we want.
这是布尔逻辑的任意方程式 可以表示任何我们想要的内容
So that's what states look like.
这是状态的样子
Now we have to figure out what actions
现在我们要计算动作的样子
look like and what the results of those action looks like.
和这些动作带来的结果
And these are represented in classical form,
这些通过经典形式
classical planning by something called an action schema,
在经典规划中通过所谓的动作模式展现出来
and it's called the schema because it represents
之所以称为模式 是因为它表示了
many possible actions that are similar to each other.
许多类似的可能动作
So let's take an example of,
我们来看个例子
we want to send cargo around the world
我们想要向世界运送货物
and we've got a bunch of planes in airports and we have cargo and
在机场有一批飞机 还有货物等
so on and I'll show you the action for having a plane fly from one location to another.
我将会向你展示用一架飞机从一个地点飞到另一个地点
Here's one possible representation.
这是一种可能的表现方法
We say it's an action schema so we write the word action and
我们说这是种动作模式 所以我们写上单词 动作
then we write the action operator and its arguments.
然后写上动作运算符及其赋值
So it's a fly of P from X to Y and then we list the preconditions.
即 Action (Fly (p,x,y)) 然后我们列出语句为真的前提
What needs to be true in order to be able to execute this action,
从而能够执行这个动作
and we can say something like well P better be plane,
我们可以说 P 最好是飞机 Plane (p)
it's no good trying to fly a truck or a submarine.
让卡车或潜水艇飞行是没有意义的
And then we'll use the end formula
然后我们要使用
from Boolean propositional logic and X better be an airport.
布尔命题逻辑中的最终公式 X 最好是机场 Airport (x)
We don't want to try to take off from my backyard.
我们没办法从我家后院起飞
Similarly Y, that'd would be an airport.
同样 Y 也是个机场 Airport (y)
And most importantly P better be at airport X in order to take off from there.
最重要的是 P 最好位于机场 X 从而可以在这儿起飞 At (p,x)
And then we represent the effects of the action by saying,
然后我们表示动作的效果
well what's going to happen?
例如将会发生什么？
Well once we fly from X to Y,
一旦我们从 X 飞到 Y
the plane is no longer at X so we say not at P,
飞机不再位于 X 所以说 ﹁At (p,x)
X, plane's no longer at X, and the plane is now at Y.
而现在飞机位于 Y 即 At (p,y)
So this is called an action schema.
这就称为动作模式
It represents a set of actions for all possible planes,
这表现了飞机可能存在的一系列动作
for all X and for all Y,
对于所有 x 和 y
represents all those actions in one schema that says what we need to know in order
表示所有这些动作都在一个模式中 说明
to apply the action and it says what will
为了实施动作 我们需要了解的内容
happen in terms of the transition from state spaces,
根据状态空间的转变会发生什么
this variable will become false and this one will become true.
这个变量为假 而这个变量为真
Now, when we look at this formula,
现在我们来看这个公式时
this looks like a term in first order logic,
它看起来像一阶逻辑的项
but we're actually dealing with completely propositional world.
但实际上我们解决充分命题世界
It just looks like that because this is a schema and we can
因为这是个模式 所以看起来是这个样子的
apply this schema to specific ground states,
我们可以在特定地面状态
specific world states, and then P and X would have specific values and you could just
特定世界状态 实施这个模式 然后 P 和 X 就会有特定值
think of it as concatenating their names all
你只需要将他们的名字全部串接起来
together and that's just the name of one variable.
这就是一个变量的名字
The name just happens to have this complex form with parentheses and commas in it to
这个名字恰好是包括括号和逗号在内的复杂形式
make it easier to write one schema that covers all individual fly actions. 最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6
为了在一个模式中书写更加简便 涉及了所有单独的飞行动作